

## Nathan Eastell

E: nathaneastelldesign@gmail.com

## **Profile**

An energetic and ambitious product designer with five years of industry experience living in Melbourne, Australia. Highly motivated and creative individual that has a strong coherent creative background, specialising in product design. Extremely resourceful and driven individual with a keen eye for detailed design. Uses strong organizational and technical skills to deliver multiple projects on time and within budget.

## **Experience**

Camp Chipinaw, Set Construction (2 month contract)

June 2019 - August 2019

Two month theatre contract position. Lived as a specialist bunk councillor with the children. Tasked with the follow responsibilities;

- Designing and construction of set
- Installing Set on sage
- Overseeing theatre productions and helping back stage
- Looking after all children on camp and within own bunk

Martech OEM, Product Design Engineer

August 2014 - May 2019

Started out as a graduate design engineer and worked my way up through the company from the Engineering department to the New Product Development team. Tasked with the following responsibilities;

- New product development from idea to manufacture
- Design updates and development of existing products
- Concept and idea generation
- Redesigning existing products for custom applications
- Bill of materials creation and management
- Model making and prototyping / proofing designs
- Liaising with foreign and local suppliers regarding manufacturing and quoting of components
- Creating and teaching SOP's (Pre-Production Build) to production team for new products
- Over seeing of quality checks on first samples of newly manufactured component
- Working to ISO 9001 standards
- Managing multiple projects simultaneously

## **Education**

University of Huddersfield, Product Design

September 2011 - June 2014

Graduated the University of Huddersfield with a Bachelor of Arts Degree in Product Design Achieving a 2:1

Programs	SolidWorks	Adobe Creative Suite	SAGE 300	Microsoft Office	
Manufacturing techniques	Sheet metal	Injection Molding	High Pressure Die Casting	Aluminum Extrusion	Plastic Extrusion
Skills	Sketching Model Making	Concept Generation Idea Proving	Computer Renders Independent and team worker	Project Presentation 2D Drafting	
Hobbies	Snowboarding	Football	Camping and Exploration	Exercise	Gaming